ANDREA CAVALLO

PhD student at TU Delft - Learning and processing over dynamic graphs

SUMMARY

I am a PhD student at TU Delft working on learning and processing over dynamic graphs. I hold a M.Sc. Degree in Computer Engineering and Artificial Intelligence from Politecnico di Torino, where I worked as a research assistant on network traffic data analysis using Graph Machine Learning techniques. My Master Thesis focuses on Graph Neural Networks and their limitations when applied to heterophilous graphs. I also worked with Explainable AI applied to the healthcare world. I enjoy diving into the details of Machine Learning algorithms, understanding their limitations and trying to explain the motivations behind their predictions. I am also fascinated by the impact these algorithms can have in real-world scenarios, and I aim to improve them and solve challenging problems.

CONTACT

a.cavallo@tudelft.nl

+39 3394533688 Delft, Netherlands

andrea-cavallo-98.github.io

@andrea-cavallo-98

Andrea Cavallo

in Andrea Cavallo

SKILLS

Programming

Advanced: Python

Intermediate: C. C++, SOI

Basic: Java, JavaScript

Software & Tools

Advanced: Pytorch, Numpy

Intermediate: Pandas, MATLAB, ETEX

Basic: TensorFlow, Hadoop, Spark, React, Git

Main ML and CS topics

- Machine Learning and Deep Learning: Graph Machine Learning, Explainable AI, Computer Vision, **Natural Language Processing**
- Computer Science: Databases (DBMS and Data Warehouses), Operating Systems (Unix/Linux environment and concurrent programming), Computer Networks, Cybersecurity, Embedded Systems

PUBLICATIONS

- Gioacchini L.; Cavallo A.; Mellia M.; Vassio L.; Exploring Temporal GNN Embeddings for Darknet Traffic Analysis. In Proceedings of the 2nd on Graph Neural Networking Workshop 2023 (GNNet '23). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 31-36. https://doi.org/10.1145/3630049.3630175
- Cavallo, A.; Grohnfeldt, C.; Russo, M.; Lovisotto, G.; Vassio, L.; GCNH: A Simple Method For Representation Learning On Heterophilous Graphs, IJCNN 2023, https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10896
- Cavallo, A.; Grohnfeldt, C.; Russo, M.; Lovisotto, G.; Vassio, L.; 2-hop Neighbor Class Similarity (2NCS): A graph structural metric indicative of graph neural network performance, accepted at AAAI GCLR 2023, https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.13202

LANGUAGES

EDUCATION

10/2023 - ongoing **♀** TU Delft. Delft

PhD Program

• Topic: Learning and Processing over Dynamic Graphs

Supervisor: Prof. Elvin Isufi

10/2022 10/2022

Politecnico di Torino, Turin

Master's - Computer Engineering

• Specific track: Artificial Intelligence and Data Analytics

- Final grade: 110/110 cum laude (GPA: 29.6/30)
- Master Thesis: Graph Neural Networks on heterophilous graphs: performance analysis and new architectures, supervised by Prof. Luca Vassio, Dr. Claas Grohnfeldt, Michele Russo and Dr. Giulio Lovisotto

1 02/2021 - 09/2022

Excellence Program Q Alta Scuola Politecnica, Turin - Milan

- Program involving the best 150 students from Politecnico di Torino and Politecnico di Milano
- Participated in conferences and group activities on innovation, management of change, design and complex decision making
- Realized a Clinical Decision Support System (NEAR) based on Explainable AI in collaboration with Dedalus, a leading company in software for healthcare

1 09/2017 - 09/2020

Bachelor's - Electronic Engineering

- **Politecnico di Torino**, Turin • Final grade: 110/110 cum laude (GPA: 29.88/30)
- Member of Percorso Giovani Talenti, a program for the best 200 students in the university

6 08/2019 - 12/2019

Viniversity of Georgia, Athens, GA, USA

Exchange Program

· Won a scholarship to finance the program

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/11/2022 - 30/09/2023 Politecnico di Torino, Turin

Research Assistant

• Performed research on network traffic data analysis using dynamic Graph Neural Networks

1 01/04/2022 - 30/09/2022

Research Intern Q Huawei Munich Research Center. Munich

• Performed research on Node Anomaly Detection and Graph Neural Networks on heterophilous graphs for the Master Thesis

m 01/10/2021 - 30/06/2022

♀ Team PoliTOcean, Turin

Computer Vision team member

· Implemented computer vision tasks (line detection, object detection) for an ROV to take part in the international Mate ROV Competition

1 01/04/2020 - 30/06/2021

♀ Team Icarus PoliTo. Turin

Machine Learning team member

• Applied Machine Learning algorithms for flight parameters estimation and trajectory prediction

15/01/2020 - 29/02/2020

♥ WeStudents s.r.l., Turin

Data Analyst

Applied ML techniques to improve the design and analyze customers' behavior for a mobile app

SELECTED RESEARCH PROJECTS

Graph Neural Networks on heterophilous graphs 🗷 🗗 🖸

- Defined 2NCS, a new metric to characterize a graph property that affects GNN performance
- Designed and tested GCNH, a simple GNN model that achieves SOTA results on both homophilous and heterophilous graphs

Network traffic data analysis with Graph Neural Networks

Applied GNNs to network traffic data to learn the behavior of nodes in an unsupervised and self-supervised manner.

Explainable AI for cardiac event risk prediction 🗹

- Implemented NEAR, an explainable ML-based model to predict the risk of cardiac events
- The explainable model is built based on the explanations provided by SHAP